const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",t=200,i=120,a=[{id:150,question:"Which of the following shows little or no net reaction when the volume of the system is decreased",option:{a:" H2(g)  +  l2(g)  ⇌  2Hl(g)",b:"2NO2(g)  ⇌  N2O4(g)",c:" PCl5(g)   ⇌ PCl3(g)  + Cl2(g)",d:" 203(g)   ⇌  3O2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:242,question:"The gas obtained as a product of anaerobic action ob organic matter buried in the earth is",option:{a:"Nitrogen(IV) oxide",b:"Carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Methane",d:"Ethene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:301,question:"One of the major uses of Alkanes is",option:{a:"In the hydrogenation of oils",b:"In the textile industries",c:"In the production of plastics",d:"As domestic and industrial fuels"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:291,question:"When iron is exposed to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Anahydrous  iron (III) oxide",b:"Anhydrous iron (II) oxide",c:"Hydrated iron (II) oxide",d:"Hydrated iron  (III) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:108,question:"The salt that will form a precipitate soluble in excess ammonia solution is",option:{a:"Ca(NO3)2",b:"Cu(NO3)2",c:"Mg(NO3)2",d:"Al(NO3)3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:66,question:"The postulate of Dalton’s atomic theory which still holds is that",option:{a:"Particles of different elements combine in a simple whole number ratio",b:"Atoms can neither be created nor destroyed",c:"The particles of the same element are exactly alike",d:"All elements are made of small indivisible particles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:85,question:"When cathode rays are detected onto the electrode of an electrometer, the instrument becomes",option:{a:"Negatively charged",b:"Positively charged",c:"Neutral",d:"Bipolar"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:91,question:"What mass of K2CrO4 is required to prepare 250cm3 of 0.020 mol dm-3 solution   [K2CrO4 = 194.2g mol-1]",option:{a:"0.97g",b:"9.70g",c:"19.42g",d:"97.10g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:89,question:"The structural component that makes detergent dissolve more quickly in water than soap is",option:{a:"–SO3 –Na+",b:"–COO-Na+",c:"–SO4- Na+",d:"–COO-K+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:285,question:"If a reaction is exothermic and thee is a great disorder, it means that",option:{a:"The reaction is in a state of equilibrium",b:"There will be a large increase in free energy",c:"There will be a large decrease in free energy",d:"The reaction is static"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:102,question:"When sugar is dissolved in tea, the reaction is always accompanied by",option:{a:"Positive entropy change",b:"Negative entropy change",c:"No entropy change",d:"A minimum entropy change"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:241,question:"Nigerian crude oil is described as light crude because of its",option:{a:"Low aliphatic hydrocarbon content",b:"Low sulphur content",c:"High natural gas content",d:"High octane number"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:1,question:"25cm3 of a gas X contains Zmolecules at 150C and 75mmHg. How many molecules will 25cmm3 of another gas Y contain at the same temperature and pressure",option:{a:"2Y",b:"2Z",c:"Z",d:"Y"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:109,question:"The metal that liberates hydrogen from cold water in bubbles only is",option:{a:"Na",b:"K",c:"Ca",d:"Al"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:293,question:"Stainless steel is used for making",option:{a:"Tools",b:"Coins and medals",c:"Moving parts of clocks",d:"Magnets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:194,question:"How many hydrogen atoms does a single ring cycloalkane have less than the corresponding open- chain alkane",option:{a:"Three",b:"One",c:"Four",d:"Two"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:127,question:"According to Charles  law, the volume of a gas becomes zero at",option:{a:"00C",b:"-1000C",c:"-2730C",d:"-3730C"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:184,question:"A heterogeneous mixture can be defined as any mixture",option:{a:"Whose composition is uniform",b:"Whose composition is not uniform",c:"Formed by solids and liquids",d:"Of a solute and a solvent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:213,question:"Which of the following equimolar solutions will have the highest pH",option:{a:"NH4OH",b:"CH3COONa",c:"HCI",d:"NaOH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:177,question:"The ores that can be concentrated by flotation are",option:{a:"Nitride ores",b:"Chloride ores",c:"Oxide ores",d:"Sulphide ores"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:221,question:"Forms a layer of oxide on the metal   If the heat of combustion of hydrogen is -285.8kJ. what is the heat of formation of water",option:{a:"-285.8Kj",b:"-571.6kJ",c:"+571kJ",d:"+285.8kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:180,question:"When pure aluminum metal is heated to red hot in the presence of nitrogen gas, the compound formed is",option:{a:"AI2N",b:"AIN",c:"AI2N2",d:"AI2N3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:222,question:"In the electrolysis of CuSO4(aq) using platinum electrodes, the reaction at the anode is",option:{a:"4H+  +  4e-  → 2H2",b:"2OH  +  2OH-  →  2H2O + O2",c:"2OH-  - 2e-    → 2OH",d:"4OH-  -  4e- →  2H2O + O2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:23,question:"C(s) + 2S (g)  → CS2 (g)      Δ H = +89kJ mol-1. The chemical equation above implies that",option:{a:"Each of carbon and sulphur has 89kJ of energy",b:"Both carbon and sulphur contribute 89kJ of energy",c:"89kJ of energy is released",d:"89kJ is absorbed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:302,question:"The haloalkanes used in the dry cleaning industries are",option:{a:"Chloroethane and dichloroethene",b:"trichloroethene and tetrachloroethene",c:"chloromethane and dichloroethene",d:"Trichloromethane and tetrachloromethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:220,question:"Trioxonitrate(V) acid is not used for preparing hydrogen gas from metals because it",option:{a:"Renders the metal passive",b:"Is strongly oxidizing",c:"Is volatile",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:36,question:"When chlorine is passed into water and the resulting solution exposed to sunlight, the product formed are",option:{a:"Chlorine gas and hydrogen",b:"Oxygen and oxochlorate(l) acid",c:"Hydrochloric acid and oxygen",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:79,question:"3Cu  +  pHNO3  → 3Cu(NO3)2  +  4H2O  + xNO   In the equation above, the values of p and x respectively are",option:{a:"1 and 3",b:"2 and 3",c:"6 and 2",d:"8 and 2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:237,question:"Which of the following has an isomer",option:{a:"C4H10",b:"C6H6",c:"C2H4",d:"C2H6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:93,question:"When 10g of sodium hydroxide is dissolved in 1000cm3 of water, the solution formed is approximately   [Na = 23, H = 1, O = 16]",option:{a:"0.01 mol dm-3",b:"0.10 mol dm-3",c:"0.25 mol dm-3",d:"0.50 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:159,question:"Sodium metal is always kept under oil because it",option:{a:"Readily reacts with water",b:"Is reduced by atmospheric nitrogen",c:"Reacts vigorously on exposure to air",d:"Reacts with oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:251,question:"The raw material used for the smelting of iron ore in a furnace is",option:{a:"Zn(NO3)2",b:"CaSO4",c:"CuSO4",d:"CaCO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:269,question:"Elements in the same periodic table have the same",option:{a:"Atomic number",b:"Chemical properties",c:"Physical properties",d:"Number of shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:153,question:"Which steam is passed over red-hot carbon, the substances produced are",option:{a:"Hydrogen and trioxocarbonate(IV) acid",b:"Hydrogen, oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Hydrogen and carbon (II) oxide",d:"Hydrogen and carbon (IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:45,question:"Which of the following gases contains the least number of atoms at s.t.p",option:{a:"4 moles of chlorine",b:"3 moles of ozone",c:"1 mole of butane",d:"7 moles of argon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:62,question:"The processes which return carbon(IV) oxide to the atmosphere include",option:{a:"Photosynthesis, decay and respiration",b:"Photosynthesis, respiration and transpiration",c:"Respiration, decay and combustion",d:"Ozone, depletion, combustion and decay"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:231,question:"A particle that contain s 11protons, 12 neutrons and 10 electrons is probably a",option:{a:"Metallic ion",b:"Non-metallic ion",c:"Neutral metal",d:"Neutral non-metal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:219,question:"Zinc and carbon rods are used as anode and cathode respectively in a",option:{a:"Voltaic cell",b:"Lead accumulator",c:"Leclanche cell",d:"Daniel cell"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:165,question:"Vulcanization involves the removal of",option:{a:"A monomer",b:"The single bond",c:"The double bond",d:"A polymer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:54,question:"The furring of kettles is caused by the presence in water of",option:{a:"Calcium trioxocarbonate(IV)",b:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",c:"CALCIUM HYDROXIDE",d:"Calcium hydrofentrioxocarbonate(IV)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:13,question:"What is the decrease in volume of air when pyrogallol is shaken with 30.00cm3 of air",option:{a:"15.00cm3",b:"6.00cm3",c:"0.63cm3",d:"0.06cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:131,question:"The shape of the s-orbital is",option:{a:"Spherical",b:"Elliptical",c:"Spiral",d:"Circular"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:257,question:"Group IA metals are not found free in nature because they",option:{a:"Have high melting and boiling points",b:"Conduct heat and electricity",c:"Are very reactive and unstable",d:"Are malleable and ductile"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:235,question:"The idea of planetary electrons was that of",option:{a:"Bohr",b:"Thompson",c:"Rutherford",d:"Dalton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:223,question:"IN which of the following is the oxidation number of sulphur equal to -2",option:{a:"H2S",b:"SO3",c:"S8",d:"SO2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:149,question:" N2O4(g)    ⇌  2NO2(g)",option:{a:"A constant volume",b:"An increase in pressure",c:"A decrease in pressure",d:" A decrease in volume"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:182,question:"The pressure of 100cm3 of oxygen at 350C is 750mmHg. What will be the volume of the gas if the pressure is reduced to 100mmHg  without changing the temperature",option:{a:"850cm3",b:"750cm3",c:"650cm3",d:"580cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:75,question:"What volume of oxygen is produced from the decomposition of 2 moles of KClO3 at s.t.p   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4 dm3]",option:{a:"22.4 dm3",b:"33.6 dm3",c:"44.8 dm3",d:"67.2 dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:283,question:"What quantity of aluminum is deposited when a current of 10A is passed through a solution of an aluminum salt for 1930s  {AI = 27, F = 96500 C mol-}",option:{a:"1.8g",b:"5.4g",c:"14.2g",d:"0.2g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:201,question:"Kerosene is commonly used to remove the red colour stain of palm oil from clothes because it",option:{a:"Helps to spread the oil over a larger surface area",b:"Makes the oil evaporate easily by dissolving it",c:"Helps to dilute the oil and reduce its colour",d:"Reacts with the oil to form an odourless compound"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:272,question:"Substances employed as drying agents are usually",option:{a:"Hygroscopic",b:"Efflorescent",c:"Acidic",d:"Amphoteric"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:110,question:"Chlorine gas turns a damp starch-iodide paper",option:{a:"Pink",b:"Colourless",c:"Red",d:"Dark blue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:87,question:"A consequence of global warming is",option:{a:"Air pollution",b:"Water pollution",c:"Increased humidity",d:"Flooding"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:203,question:"The solubility curve shows the variation of solute concentration with",option:{a:"Volume",b:"Vapour density",c:"Pressure",d:"Temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:16,question:"Phosphorous is stored under water to precvent it from",option:{a:"Dehydrating",b:"Becoming inert",c:"Smelling",d:"Catching fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:7,question:"Four elements W, X, Y, and Z have atomic numbers 2, 6, 16 and 20 respectively. Which of these elements is a metal",option:{a:"X",b:"W",c:"Z",d:"Y"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:229,question:"[Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p + 22.4dm3} Nuclear fission involves the splitting of a heavy element into two nuclei of",option:{a:"Equal masses with a release of energy",b:"Nearly equal masses with a release of energy and radiation",c:"Equal masses with a release of energy and radiation",d:"Unequal masses without any release of energy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:97,question:"Which of the following will change when a catalyst is added to a chemical reaction",option:{a:"The activation energy",b:"The potential energy of the reactants",c:"The heat of reaction",d:"The potential energy of the products"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:138,question:"The solubility in mol dm-3 of 20g of CuSO4 dissolved in 100g of water at 1800C is  [Cu = 64, S = 32, O = 16]",option:{a:"0.13",b:"0.25",c:"1.25",d:"2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:135,question:"Hardness of water is caused by the presence of the ions of",option:{a:"Magnesium and silver",b:"Calcium and magnesium",c:"Sodium and potassium",d:"Calcium and sodium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:6,question:"Milikan’s contribution to the development of atomic theory is the determination of",option:{a:"Charge on electron",b:"Positive rays",c:"Charge to amss ratio",d:"Cathode rays"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:67,question:"Ordinary glass is manufactured from silica, Ca CO3 and",option:{a:"K2CO3",b:"NaHCO3",c:"Na2CO3",d:"K2SO4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:248,question:"An emulsion may be produced by shaking a detergent solution with",option:{a:"Palm wine",b:"Palm oil",c:"Ethanoic acid",d:"Water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:31,question:"The general formula for the alkanals is",option:{a:"ROH",b:"R2CO",c:"RCOOR1",d:"RCHO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:247,question:"Water has the ability to dissolve almost all substances because its molecule has a structure with",option:{a:"One positive end and one neutral end",b:"Two positive ends",c:"One positive end and one negative end",d:"Two negative ends"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:196,question:"In the purification of impure samples of ethyl ethanoate synthesized by esterification, concentrated sodium trioxocarbonate(IV) solution is used to remove",option:{a:"Water",b:"Acidic impurities",c:"Basic impurities",d:"Ethoxyethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:52,question:"The substance least considered as a source of environmental pollution is",option:{a:"Silicate minerals",b:"Uranium",c:"Lead compounds",d:"Organophosphorous compounds"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:263,question:"The droplets of water observed around a bottle of milk taken out of though refrigerator is due to the fact that the",option:{a:"Temperature of the milk drops as it loses heat into the surroundings",b:"Saturated vapour pressure of the milk is equal to the atmospheric pressure",c:"Water vapour in the air around loses some of its energy to the bottle",d:"Water vapour in the air around the bottle gains some energy from the bottle"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:287,question:"2H2(g) +    O2(g)  ⇌ 2H2O(g)    ΔH   =  - ve  What happens to the equilibrium constant of the reaction above if the temperature is increased?",option:{a:"It becomes zero",b:"It decreases",c:"It increases",d:"It is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:178,question:"The most suitable metal that can be used as a lightening  conductor is",option:{a:"Aluminium",b:"Iron",c:"Copper",d:"Silver"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:175,question:"N2(g)  +  3H2(g)  ⇌   2NH2(g)   Δ H = - 90kJ  In the equation above, the yield of ammonia can be decreased by",option:{a:"Adding a catalyst",b:"Removing ammonia",c:"Increasing the pressure",d:"Increasing the temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:92,question:"Farmlands affected by crude –oil spillage can be decontaminated by",option:{a:"Adding acidic solutions",b:"Using aerobic bacteria",c:"Pouring water on the affected area",d:"Burning off the oil from the area"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:126,question:"What volume of gas is evolved at s.t.p. if 2g of calcium trioxocarbonate(IV) is added to a solution of hydrochloric acid    [Ca = 40, C = 12, O = 16, CI = 35.5, H = 1, Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm3]",option:{a:"112cm3",b:"224cm3",c:"448cm3",d:"224cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:279,question:"Which of the following salts is slightly soluble in water",option:{a:"CaSO4",b:"Na2CO3",c:"PbCl2",d:"AgCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:250,question:"Dynamic equilibrium describes a situation where",option:{a:"A reaction gives back the reactants",b:"Reactants are converted to products",c:"The concentration of reactants and products is equal",d:"Both forward and reverse reaction proceed at the same rate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:193,question:"Equal moles of ethyne and hydrogen iodide react to give",option:{a:"CH2 = CH2",b:"CH2 = CHI",c:"CH2 – CHI",d:"CH2 – CI3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:207,question:"In which of the following reactions can the oxidation number of nitrogen be said to have increased",option:{a:"FeSO4(aq)  +  NO(g) →   Fe(NO)SO4(S)",b:"2NO(g)  +  O2(g) → 2NO2(g)",c:"NO(g)  +  CI2(g)  → NOCI2(l)",d:"NO(g)  +  Br2(l)   → NOBr2(l)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:56,question:"When a salt loses its water of crystallization to the atmosphere on exposure, the process is said to be",option:{a:"Deliquescence",b:"Effervescence",c:"Efflorescence",d:"Fluorescence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:286,question:"In the preparation of oxygen by heating KCIO3 in the presence of MnC2, only moderate hear is needed because the catalyst acts by",option:{a:"Increasing the surface area of the reactant",b:"Increasing the rate of the reaction",c:"Lowering the energy barrier of the reaction",d:"Lowering the pressure of the reaction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:69,question:"Hydrogen is readily released when dilute hydrochloric acid reacts with",option:{a:"Au",b:"Cu",c:"Na",d:"Ag"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:76,question:"Which of the following is a physical change",option:{a:"Burning kerosene",b:"Freezing ice-cream",c:"Exposing white phosphorus to air",d:"Dissolving calcium in water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:212,question:"What will happen if an aluminum spoon is used to stir a solution of iron (II) trioxonitrate(V)",option:{a:"The spoon will be reduced while the iron(II) ions will be oxidized",b:"The spoon will be oxidized while the iron (II) ions will be reduced to the metal",c:"The spoon will be reduced",d:"The spoon will increase in size"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:254,question:"The efficiency of a solid catalyst to increase reaction rates depends on its",option:{a:"Concentration",b:"Solubility",c:"Quantity",d:"Surface area"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:8,question:"An element X with relative atomic mass 16.2 contains two isotopes      X  with relative abundance of 90% and      X with relative abundance of 10%. The value of m is",option:{a:"16",b:"18",c:"12",d:"14"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:245,question:"When 5.0cm3 of a saturated solution of sugar of molar mass 342g at 400C was evaporated to dryness, 34.2g of dry solid was obtained. The solubility of sugar at 400C is",option:{a:"7.0 mol dm-3",b:"3.5 mol dm-3",c:"2.0 mol dm-3",d:"10.0mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:183,question:"What is the valence shell electron configuration of the element with atomic number 17",option:{a:"1s22s22p63s23p5",b:"1s22s22p63s23p4",c:"3s23p5",d:"2s22p6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:284,question:"In which of the following is the entropy change positive",option:{a:"Reaction between an acid and a base",b:"Addition of concentrated acid to water",c:"Dissolution of sodium metal in water",d:"Thermal dissociation of ammonium chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:32,question:"The main impurity in iron ore during the extraction of iron is",option:{a:"Silicon (IV) oxide",b:"Carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Calciumtrioxosilicate",d:"Sulphur(II) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:288,question:"To a solution of an unknown compound, a little dilute Tetraoxosulphate (IV) acid was added with some freshly prepared (II) Tetraoxosulphate (VI) Solution. The brown ring observed after the addition of a stream of concentrated  Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid confirmed the presence of",option:{a:"CI",b:"SO",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:39,question:"The pair of organic compounds that are isomers is",option:{a:"Benzene and methylbenzene",b:"Trichloromethane and Tetrachloromethane",c:"Ethanol and propanone",d:"But-1-ene and but-2-ene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:114,question:"How many isomers does pentane have",option:{a:"6",b:"5",c:"4",d:"3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:206,question:"The gas that is the most dangerous pollutant to humans is",option:{a:"Carbon(IV) oxide",b:"Nitrogen (II)oxide",c:"Hydrogen sulphide",d:"Sulphur(IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:55,question:"Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid burns the skin by",option:{a:"Heating",b:"Hydration",c:"Dehydration",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:274,question:"Coffee stains can best be removed by",option:{a:"Turpentine",b:"A solution of borax in water",c:"Ammonia solution",d:"Kerosene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:202,question:"25cm3 of a mixture of noble gases was obtained from air after the removal of other constituents. What was the original volume of air",option:{a:"125cm3",b:"1250cm3",c:"2500cm3",d:"80cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:230,question:"2C2H2(g)  +  5O2(g)     4CO2(g)  +  2H2O(g) In the reaction, the mass of carbon (IV) oxide produced on burning 78g of ethyne is [C = 12, O = 16, H = 1]",option:{a:"39",b:"352g",c:"264g",d:"156g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:146,question:"The mass of silver deposited when a current of 10A is passed through a solution of silver salt for 4830s is    [Ag = 108, F = 96500 Cmol-1]",option:{a:"108.0g",b:"54.0g",c:"27.0g",d:"13.5g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:107,question:"Which of the following statements is true of sulphur (IV) oxide",option:{a:"It forms Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid with water",b:"It is an odourless gas",c:"It is an acid anhydride",d:"It forms white precipitate with acidified barium chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:57,question:"Three drops of a 1.0 mol dm-3 solution of Na OH are added to 20cm3 of a solution of pH8.4. the pH of the resulting solution will be",option:{a:"Greater than 8.4",b:"Unaltered",c:"Close to that of pure water",d:"Less than 8.4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:172,question:"In a flame test for calcium, the flame appears",option:{a:"Blue when viewed through a blue glass",b:"Green when viewed through a blue glass",c:"Orange-red when viewed through a blue glass",d:"Brick-red when viewed through a blue glass"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:140,question:"Which of these compounds is a normal salt",option:{a:"NaHS",b:"NaSO4",c:"NaHCO3",d:"Na2CO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:119,question:"A compound contains 40.0% carbon, 6.7% hydrogen and 53.3% oxygen. If the molar mass of the compound is 180, find the molecular formula  [H = 1, C = 12, O = 16]",option:{a:"CH2O",b:"C3H6O3",c:"C6H12O6",d:"C6H6O3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:208,question:"A concentrated solution containing H+, Cu2+, OH- and Cl- was electrolyzed using platinum electrodes. The ion that will be discharged at the cathode is",option:{a:"OH-",b:"Cl-",c:"Cu2+",d:"H+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:259,question:"The ion that will give a white precipitate with aqueous NaOH and soluble in excess of the base is",option:{a:"Zn2+",b:"Mg2+",c:"Ca2+",d:"Cu2+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:303,question:" Two hydrocarbons X and Y were treated with bromine water. Decolorized the solution and Y did not. Which class of compound does Y belong",option:{a:"Alkynes",b:"Alkenes",c:"Alkanes",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:176,question:"Metalloids are also referred to as",option:{a:"Metals",b:"Semi-metals",c:"Colloids",d:"Non-metals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:41,question:"The gas that can best be collected by downward displacement of air is",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Sulphur(IV)oxide",c:"Ammonia",d:"Carbon(IV)oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:96,question:"The commonest feature of the reactions at the anode is that",option:{a:"Electrons are consumed",b:"Oxidation is involved",c:"Ions are reduced",d:"Electrode dissolves"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:158,question:"Transition metals posses variable oxidation states because they have",option:{a:"Electrons in the d orbitals",b:"Electrons in the s orbitals",c:"A variable number of electrons in the p orbitals",d:"Partially filled p orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:141,question:"What volume of 0.5mol dm-3 H2SO4 will exactly neutralize 20cm3 of 0.1 mol dm-3 NaOH solution",option:{a:"2.0cm3",b:"5.0cm3",c:"6.8cm3",d:"8.3cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:105,question:"Metals of the first transition series have special proper ties which are different from those of groups I and II elements because they have partially filled",option:{a:"s  orbitals",b:"p orbitals",c:"d orbitals",d:"f orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:27,question:"As the concentration of an electrolyte reduces, the conductivity",option:{a:"Reduces to zero",b:"Decreases",c:"Increases",d:"Is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:249,question:"One heating may be produced by shaking a detergent solution with",option:{a:"Cu(NO3)2",b:"AgNO3",c:"Ca(NO3)2",d:"NaNO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:25,question:"3CU(s)  +  8HNO3(aq) →  3Cu(NO3)2(aq)  +  4H2O(I)  +  2NO(g)  In the equation above, copper is",option:{a:"An electron acceptor",b:"A base",c:"An oxidizing agent",d:"A reducing agent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:60,question:"which of the following chlorides would exhibit the least ionic character",option:{a:"AlCl3",b:"CaCl2",c:"MgCi2",d:"LiCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:190,question:"Which of these properties gives a solid its definite shape",option:{a:"Weak intermolecular attraction",b:"High boiling point",c:"High melting point",d:"Strong intermolecular attraction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:185,question:"The density of a certain gas is 1.98g dm-3 at s.t.p. What is the molecular mass of the gas   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm-3]",option:{a:"26.0g",b:"31.0g",c:"54.0g",d:"44.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:130,question:"An electron can be added to a halogen atom to form a halide ion with",option:{a:"2 valence electrons",b:"3 valence electrons",c:"7 valence electrons",d:"Valence electrons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:192,question:"Sugar is separated from its impurities by",option:{a:"Distillation",b:"Evaporation",c:"Precipitation",d:"Crystallization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:162,question:"An isomer of C5H12 is",option:{a:"Butane",b:"2-methylbutane",c:"2-methylprpane",d:"2-ethylbutane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,t as status,o as subject,i as total};
